Contact

773-682-6107 (Mobile) sylwia0103@sbcglobal.net

www.linkedin.com/in/ sylviagoczolbsn (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

CNA

Nursing

EPIC

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Polish (Native or Bilingual)

Spanish (Limited Working)

Certifications

Basic Life Support for Healthcare Providers (BLS)

Registered Nurse: Illinois

Registered nurse: California

Certified Emergency Nurse (CEN)

Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support Experienced Provider (ACLS)

Honors-Awards

Magna Cum Laude Scholastic Silver Medallion Interdisciplinary Honors Program

Sylvia Goczol, BSN, RN, CEN

Emergency Nurse and Master of Social Work Student Chicago, Illinois

Summary

Emergency room nurse with 4 years of ED experience and 6 months of ICU experience. Currently in school for my Master of Social Work. High energy and driven. Strong organizational, prioritization, and critical-thinking skills. Able to problem-solve and multitask. Focused on providing patient-centered and family-centered care. Committed to caring for the patient and family holistically.

Devoted to lifelong learning and continuing education.

Experience

Ann & Robert H. Lurie Children's Hospital of Chicago Emergency Room Nurse December 2019 - Present (8 months)

Chicago, Illinois, United States

Aya Healthcare

9 months

Emergency Room Nurse June 2019 - November 2019 (6 months)

Greater Chicago Area

26-week assignment at Northwestern Medical Center ER

Emergency Room Nurse March 2019 - June 2019 (4 months)

Merced, California Area

13-week assignment at Mercy Medical Center ER

Merced County Department of Public Health Community Health Nurse January 2019 - March 2019 (3 months)

Merced, California Area

Provide case management of active tuberculosis patients residing in Merced County.

Conduct contact investigations for confirmed active TB cases.

Administer and read TB tests, provide TB clearances, and perform blood draws.

Conduct home visits to offer patient education and guidance.

Aya Healthcare Emergency Room Nurse September 2018 - October 2018 (2 months) Merced, California Area

13-week assignment at Mercy Medical Center ER; contract canceled due to injury

Medcor Registered Nurse May 2018 - September 2018 (5 months) Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming

Provide emergency and urgent medical care to Summer visitors and employees at Yellowstone National Park (May to September).

Use proper technique to perform radiographic images with clinic's x-ray

machine.

Register patients at front desk and collect payment after visit.

Facilitate transfer of critical patients to outside hospitals via ambulance or helicopter.

Perform limited lab testing (urinalysis, rapid strep, hematocrit, etc.) and send out additional labs to an outside clinic.

Planet Healthcare Emergency Room Registered Nurse February 2018 - May 2018 (4 months) Greater Chicago Area

Provide flexible scheduling to fill in employment gaps in Emergency Departments of hospitals in the Chicagoland area.

13-week assignment at Northwestern Medical Center ER

Nurses PRN

Emergency Room Registered Nurse December 2017 - February 2018 (3 months)

Greater Chicago Area

- Provide flexible scheduling to fill in employment gaps in Emergency Departments of hospitals in the Chicagoland area.
- Agree to a 13-week contract for each hospital, with the option for renewal.
- Uphold agency mission and values during completion of all nursing tasks.
- Follow evidence-based practice when caring for patients and their families.

Advocate Lutheran General Hospital Critical Care Registered Nurse April 2017 - November 2017 (8 months) Park Ridge

- Responsible for total patient care of 1-2 patients in a 33-bed medical-cardiac/interventional intensive care unit.
- Care for patients with critical illnesses, such as: CHF/COPD exacerbation, respiratory failure, myocardial infarction, drug overdose, DKA, acute renal failure, dysrhythmias, cardiac arrest, sepsis, GI bleed, stroke.
- Proficient in EKG interpretation and capnography with central lines (CVP catheters, arterial lines, Swanz-Ganz catheters)
- Set up, regulate and maintain life-saving or life-maintenance equipment such as ventilators, intra-aortic balloon pumps, Impella pumps, left ventricular assist devices, CVVH.
- Administrate and titrate vasopressors to maintain blood pressure goal.

Resurrection Medical Center
Emergency Room RN
October 2015 - April 2017 (1 year 7 months)

Greater Chicago Area

- Provide care to patients across the lifespan and deliver safe and effective care based on acuity level.
- Assess and treat patients during numerous interventions: cardiac arrests, stroke and STEMI codes, conscious sedations, intubations, collection of sexual assault kits, defibrillations, blood transfusions, etc.
- Instruct individuals and families on health education and disease prevention.
- Communicate and collaborate with residents, attending physicians, and other healthcare professionals to ensure optimal patient care.
- Advocate for psychiatric patients and collaborate with the crisis worker to facilitate transfer to an inpatient psychiatric unit.

Ann & Robert H. Lurie Children's Hospital of Chicago Student Nurse Assistant June 2014 - July 2015 (1 year 2 months)

In this position, I functioned in a supportive role to a registered nurse on the medical/surgical/transplant unit.

I worked collaboratively with a dynamic health care team in the management of patient care, which allowed me to gain experience in communicating and working closely with diverse patient populations and complex family concerns.

Loyola University Chicago
Desk Receptionist
August 2012 - December 2014 (2 years 5 months)

As a Desk Receptionist, I was an integral member of the Department of Residence Life, responsible for helping to facilitate a welcoming, caring, healthy and safe environment, promoting community rooted in the Jesuit tradition of Loyola University Chicago.

While working at the residence hall front desk, I assisted in the administration, service, and security of the residence hall. As the first contact to residents, visitors, and persons in and outside of the Loyola community, I demonstrated professionalism and customer service at all times, while also responding quickly and effectively in emergencies and situations involving student safety.

Our Lady of the Resurrection Medical Center Nurse Extern-registry May 2014 - August 2014 (4 months)

Our Lady of the Resurrection Medical Center (now Community First Medical Center) is dedicated to responding with compassionate medical and nursing care, as well as advanced diagnostic and treatment services that promote patients' well-being.

As a nurse extern, I performed patient care activities on the following units on an as-needed basis: ICU, ER, medical-surgical, and telemetry.

Asian Human Services, Inc.

Tutor

October 2011 - May 2012 (8 months)

The Literacy Education for Adults and Families (LEAF) Program offers yearround educational programming for low-income adults, children and families. As a tutor in the after-school program for school-age children, I assisted elementary-school students with their homework. I monitored their progress and provided feedback to them and their parents in order to promote their academic growth and development.

Education

Boston University School of Social Work Master of Social Work - MSW · (2019 - 2022)

Loyola University Chicago
Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2011 - 2015)